<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maosboo</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 09:46:45 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 09:46:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sick</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Death, a beautifully-limbed child, leaps over the walls and hedgerows. Through my illness, I watch It cross the valley. Through the morning fog, Its unwavering grin becomes clearer. It is magnificent, tracing a perfect parabola, momentarily black above a white-tipped field. The spindly tree branches reach for It, but never fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Death is small, dipping in and out of my sight. If I had previously thought of Death at all, I had thought of It as big, but It is not. I remember now hearing that, often, Death begins as a small thought, and ends in a room that becomes empty. This Death is small enough to slip through the gaps between stones and momentarily disappear, like an intermediate stage of working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look! Look now! Reappearing, rolling on the snow down the ridge, arms pressed tight to its side—it is Death! As Death rises to its feet, and approaches, I can hear each of Its steps making a sucking sound, as if the frozen dirt, extending deep beneath Its feet, is moistening. And I can feel the dirt beneath my own feet, here where I stand alone, hungering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As It draws close, I see the face of Death, still grinning, and recognise Its face immediately as mathematics, inevitable and clean, yet nonetheless stinking of its origins in the rotting human form. Epistemic logic or ontologic decay, either way, amounts to the same thing in the end. Death embraces me, within those beautiful small limbs, or, at least, embraces my left leg, and It and I sink together, into the proof of the theorem, into my rot, into the dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-20-sick/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-20-sick/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>