<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maosboo</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:00:25 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 14:00:25 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What goes up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I read that they cut off the witch’s head, but it did not fall into the wicker basket—instead, it floated upwards, gleefully. Its hair kept growing, down almost to the chimneys, until both the head and its hair were entirely eaten up by crows, leaving only the tall shadow affixed to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read that the ground was dug up in the 1930s, and that the hole became our local outdoor pool. I have come to believe that the witch still lives, in the pool’s shadows, powers waxing with the season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the water shines, the pool’s concrete edges sharp in the summer sun. My brother and I are swimming. He never spoke much, but these days he doesn’t speak at all. Mum worries. Dad says that it is a phase. My brother and I climb out of the pool, beaded, shadows across my brother’s face. The summer sluggishly passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter comes—slow and dark. I return to the pool, through a gap in the fence. The shadows are dim, blurred, the cold pool deserted. Except for my brother. He is in the water, naked. I’m not sure why, but I climb up on the diving board, shivering. He does not look at me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wait for the sun to peak, for the diving board’s shadow to swallow my brother. He speaks. After we get home, he speaks some more, and then some more. Everyone says that they are glad that the phase is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no-one says anything about my brother now saying things he should not know, about him talking to crows in the night, about him speaking the words of the witch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-what%20goes%20up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-what%20goes%20up/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mirrorsucker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mirrorsucker, they say to her, the small girl with dark hair, alone in the cool shadows of the playground. I know they say she presses her lips against mirrors, sucking on her own reflection, because no one else will have her. She and I are not friends, really—she barely speaks to anyone—but I really hate them, the ones who call her mirrorsucker. I don’t know if it’s true, the story about sucking mirrors, but I don’t know any better—they say it happens in the girls’ bathroom. But the evil I see in their eyes when they say “mirrorsucker”—that is true, all right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hot today, far too hot in our classrooms. So hot that I cannot sleep in the night. Mum and Dad are asleep, but I find myself at the front door, still too much heat in me, drawn by the smell of the cooling evening. I walk aimlessly, to the shops, not far. It is a small town, it is late—the streets are empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except, in front of the shoe shop, I see the girl. She doesn’t see me. Her face, her lips, are pressed to the mirrored shopfront, to her reflection. The more I look, the more it looks like it is the black glass that is doing the sucking, drawing her in. It seems like the other thing clearly visible in the glass, and only there, sharp-angled and clutching, needs the girl, just as much as she needs it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-mirrorsucker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-mirrorsucker/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mars base</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We buried the first person who died on Mars on the slope of a hill just outside base, and, in retrospect, it’s lucky we didn’t bury him with his access card. Now we cremate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked on the Mars base for a few years now, and my job means I do a lot of solo remote exploration, driving the truck all over. On one mission, I finally found the Curiosity rover. It was driving. When it went silent, decades ago, it was immobile and failed. So I lifted the rover, and noticed dripping. I saw it had left a wet trail, right to the horizon. My suit analysed a drop. It was blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing about remote exploration is finding a door, standing upright and alone in the middle of some plain or crater. More precisely, the worst thing is what you see on the other side of the keyhole. It is always an eye, and even more precisely, the worst thing is what is reflected in its pupil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of us out on exploration missions have seen a man from a distance. He is a tall, very thin man without a suit. We don’t talk about it much. At least we didn’t talk about it much until Hectorson disappeared, because the next time the man was seen (as it happens, by me), he looked fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my most recent mission, I found a perfect smooth sphere, made of rock. I tapped it, and the sphere opened. Inside it was a left big toe. Then the sphere closed again. Later, I repeated the trick for the Science dept, and we saw a load of odd human parts. So, it’s exactly nine days since we did all that, and my left big toe just disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-mars%20base/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-mars%20base/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fiction of length no greater than 300 words</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;300 words is not much, but as this is intended to be fiction, I will simply lie about my life, mostly by shameless omission, until my story fits. To begin, my primary reason for continuing to tolerate existence is my responsibilities, but it is exactly those responsibilities that make existence so intolerable. You may wonder—why not simply shuck off those responsibilities—but those responsibilities are all owed to people that I unambiguously love. I acknowledge that my suffering is fundamentally absurd, as bearing commitments to those I love, especially given my generous allocation of good fortune, should not lead to intolerable existence. But I think suffering is always, at its root, absurd—what meaning does our universe provide other than the vision of painted clowns dancing upon quantum foam, sinking into the foam, until all one can see are the tips of their overlong shoes. Indeed, it is clowns who leaven my depression, the clowns that I can always see, sometimes just out of the corner of my eye, sometimes beneath me, in a hole or stairwell, sometimes hiding at the top of a tree or cell-phone tower, because—clowns that no one else can see, but that move everyone’s limbs by use of strings? Absurd! Who wouldn’t get a few laughs out of that? I must declare here that a sense of humour is perhaps my most important survival skill. When my partner said that they and our children would never forgive me if I did it, I laughed, not in a mocking way, but because I had spotted my own and my partner’s mouths tugged by the clowns’ strings, and it is hard not to be somewhat entertained by the antics of the clowns, evil as they may be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-fiction%20of%20length%20no%20greater%20than%20300%20words/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-fiction%20of%20length%20no%20greater%20than%20300%20words/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A descent</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I arrive gradually, over months, one sense at a time—first, no matter what I eat, the sickly-sweet taste, then, the unshakeable smell of smoke, then, the sound of bells in the wind, then, I see the wires, strung across all things, and then, finally, I feel the touch. Then everything is soft, spongy, and I sink, all the way down to Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finally get to Hell, it is crowded. But not with figures whose eyes glow red high above, nor with chattering AIs, nor with little pig-demons with metal grins—those here to torment me are (obviously) all people I love. My tormentors press in on all sides, and soon convert my skeleton into ice, and, as the heat boils my bones out my mouth, I taste my memories in agony, whilst new ice bones reform within. Gradually, the tormentors work out which memories hurt the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the snake leers at me, its tongue bifurcating, bifurcating, bifurcating again—and, each time that the tongue bifurcates, I remember my friend from high school. In each memory, he is silent, still and cold in the dunes in the night, but each time, he is holding a different hand-written note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my memories are unwound and wound again, I slowly acquire one ghastly new sense after another, learning far too much, and, with each sense acquired, I sink a little deeper. Eventually, I find myself become a dysregulated puppet, twitching in response to string-tugs from above, an emissary to the strange countries beyond Hell’s lower borders.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-a%20descent/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-21-a%20descent/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sick</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Death, a beautifully-limbed child, leaps over the walls and hedgerows. Through my illness, I watch It cross the valley. Through the morning fog, Its unwavering grin becomes clearer. It is magnificent, tracing a perfect parabola, momentarily black above a white-tipped field. The spindly tree branches reach for It, but never fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Death is small, dipping in and out of my sight. If I had previously thought of Death at all, I had thought of It as big, but It is not. I remember now hearing that, often, Death begins as a small thought, and ends in a room that becomes empty. This Death is small enough to slip through the gaps between stones and momentarily disappear, like an intermediate stage of working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look! Look now! Reappearing, rolling on the snow down the ridge, arms pressed tight to its side—it is Death! As Death rises to its feet, and approaches, I can hear each of Its steps making a sucking sound, as if the frozen dirt, extending deep beneath Its feet, is moistening. And I can feel the dirt beneath my own feet, here where I stand alone, hungering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As It draws close, I see the face of Death, still grinning, and recognise Its face immediately as mathematics, inevitable and clean, yet nonetheless stinking of its origins in the rotting human form. Epistemic logic or ontologic decay, either way, amounts to the same thing in the end. Death embraces me, within those beautiful small limbs, or, at least, embraces my left leg, and It and I sink together, into the proof of the theorem, into my rot, into the dirt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-20-sick/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024-07-20-sick/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>